export default {
  id: 'mid_2a',
  name: '상용한자(중학2/음독찾기)',
  data: [
    { question: '坊', answer: ['동네 방', '동네', 'ぼう、[ぼっ]'] },
    { question: '妨', answer: ['방해할 방', 'さまた(げる)', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '紡', answer: ['실뽑을 방', 'つむ(ぐ)', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '肪', answer: ['기름 방', '기름', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '房', answer: ['방 방', 'ふさ', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '芳', answer: ['꽃다울 방', 'かんば(しい)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '倣', answer: ['모방할 방', 'なら(う)', 'ほう'] },
    { question: '傲', answer: ['거만할 오', 'おご(る)', 'ごう'] },
    { question: '忌', answer: ['꺼릴 기', 'い(む)、い(まわしい)', 'き'] },
    { question: '妃', answer: ['왕비 비', '왕비', 'ひ'] },
    { question: '把', answer: ['잡을 파', '잡을', 'は'] },
    { question: '甘', answer: ['달 감', 'あま(い)、あま(える)、あま(やかす)', 'かん'] },
    { question: '紺', answer: ['감색 감', '감색', 'こん'] },
    { question: '甚', answer: ['심할 심', 'はなは(だしい)', 'じん'] },
    { question: '耐', answer: ['견딜 감', 'た(える)', 'かん'] },
    { question: '勘', answer: ['헤아릴 감', '헤아릴', 'かん'] },
    { question: '某', answer: ['아무 모', '아무', 'ぼう'] },
    { question: '謀', answer: ['꾀할 모', 'はか(る)', 'ぼう、[む]'] },
    { question: '媒', answer: ['중매할 매', '중매할', 'ばい'] },
    { question: '棋', answer: ['바둑 기, 장기 기', '바둑, 장기', 'き'] },
    { question: '碁', answer: ['바둑 기, 바둑돌 기', '바둑, 바둑돌', 'ご'] },
    { question: '欺', answer: ['속일 기', 'あざむ(く)', 'ぎ'] },
    { question: '吉', answer: ['길할 길', '길할', 'きち、きつ'] },
    { question: '詰', answer: ['물을 힐', 'つ(める)、つ(まる)、つ(む)', 'きつ'] },
    { question: '痘', answer: ['천연두 두', '천연두', 'とう'] },
    { question: '闘', answer: ['싸울 투', 'たたか(う)', 'とう'] },
    { question: '壱', answer: ['한 일', '한', 'いち'] },
    { question: '弐', answer: ['두 이', '두', 'に'] },
    { question: '吐', answer: ['토할 토', 'は(く)', 'と'] },
    { question: '挫', answer: ['꺾을 좌', '꺾을', 'ざ'] },
    { question: '睦', answer: ['화목할 목', 'むつ(まじい)、むつ(む)', 'ぼく'] },
    { question: '陵', answer: ['무덤 릉', 'みささぎ', 'りょう'] },
    { question: '崖', answer: ['낭떠러지 애', 'がけ', 'がい'] },
    { question: '涯', answer: ['물가 애', '물가', 'がい'] },
    { question: '佳', answer: ['아름다울 가', '아름다울', 'か'] },
    { question: '掛', answer: ['걸 괘', 'か(ける)、か(かる)、か(かり)', ''] },
    { question: '封', answer: ['봉할 봉', '봉할', 'ふう、ほう'] },
    { question: '暁', answer: ['새벽 효', 'あかつき', 'ぎょう'] },
    { question: '牲', answer: ['희생 생', '희생', 'せい'] },
    { question: '姓', answer: ['성씨 성', '성씨', 'せい、しょう'] },
    { question: '隆', answer: ['높을 륭', '높을', 'りゅう'] },
    { question: '妊', answer: ['임신할 임', '임신할', 'にん'] },
    { question: '呈', answer: ['드릴 정', '드릴', 'てい'] },
    { question: '淫', answer: ['음란할 음', 'みだ(ら)', 'いん'] },
    { question: '廷', answer: ['조정 정', '조정', 'てい'] },
    { question: '艇', answer: ['배 정', '배', 'てい'] },
    { question: '旺', answer: ['왕성할 왕', '왕성할', 'おう'] },
    { question: '狂', answer: ['미칠 광', 'くる(う)、くる(おしい)', 'きょう'] },
    { question: '栓', answer: ['마개 전', '마개', 'せん'] },
    { question: '詮', answer: ['설명할 전', '설명할', 'せん'] },
    { question: '債', answer: ['빚 채', '빚', 'さい'] },
    { question: '漬', answer: ['담글 지', 'つ(ける)、つ(かる)', ''] },
    { question: '請', answer: ['청할 청', 'こ(う)、う(ける)', 'せい、[しん]'] },
    { question: '銘', answer: ['새길 명', '새길', 'めい'] },
    { question: '釜', answer: ['가마 부', 'かま', 'ふ'] },
    { question: '絡', answer: ['이을 락', 'から(む)、から(まる)、から(める)', 'らく'] },
    { question: '悟', answer: ['깨달을 오', 'さと(る)', 'ご'] },
    { question: '枯', answer: ['마를 고', 'か(れ)る、か(らす)', 'こ'] },
    { question: '錮', answer: ['금고 고', '금고', 'こ'] },
    { question: '箇', answer: ['낱 개', '낱', 'か'] },
    { question: '諾', answer: ['허락할 락(낙)', '허락할', 'だく'] },
    { question: '匿', answer: ['숨길 닉', '숨길', 'とく'] },
    { question: '苛', answer: ['가혹할 가', '가혹할', 'か'] },
    { question: '奇', answer: ['기이할 기', '기이할', 'き'] },
    { question: '埼', answer: ['갑 기', '[さい]', ''] },
    { question: '崎', answer: ['험할 기', 'さき', ''] },
    { question: '騎', answer: ['말탈 기', '말탈', 'き'] },
    { question: '椅', answer: ['의자 의', '의자', 'い'] },
    { question: '伺', answer: ['엿볼 사', 'うかがう', 'し'] },
    { question: '嗣', answer: ['이을 사', '이을', 'し'] },
    { question: '妬', answer: ['질투할 투', 'ねたむ', 'と'] },
    { question: '拓', answer: ['개척할 척, 박을 탁', '개척할, 박을', 'たく'] },
    { question: '吏', answer: ['관리 리', '관리', 'り'] },
    { question: '沖', answer: ['화할 충', 'おき', 'ちゅう'] },
    { question: '串', answer: ['땅이름 곶, 꿸 관, 꿰미 천', 'くし', ''] },
    { question: '患', answer: ['근심 환', 'わずら(う)', 'かん'] },
    { question: '呂', answer: ['법칙 려', '법칙', 'ろ'] },
    { question: '侶', answer: ['짝 려', '짝', 'りょ'] },
    { question: '楼', answer: ['다락 루', '다락', 'ろう'] },
    { question: '琴', answer: ['거문고 금', 'こと', 'きん'] },
    { question: '吟', answer: ['읊을 음', '읊을', 'きん'] },
    { question: '含', answer: ['머금을 함', 'ふく(む)、ふく(める)', 'がん'] },
    { question: '捻', answer: ['비틀(짜낼) 념', '비틀(짜낼)', 'ねん'] },
    { question: '貪', answer: ['탐낼 탐', 'むさぼ(る)', 'どん'] },
    { question: '倹', answer: ['검소할 검', '검소할', 'けん'] },
    { question: '剣', answer: ['칼 검', 'つるぎ', 'けん'] },
    { question: '塔', answer: ['탑 탑', '탑', 'とう'] },
    { question: '搭', answer: ['탈 탑', '탈', 'とう'] },
    { question: '晶', answer: ['맑을 정', '맑을', 'しょう'] },
    { question: '宴', answer: ['잔치 연', '잔치', 'えん'] },
    { question: '冥', answer: ['어두울 명', '어두울', 'めい、みょう'] },
    { question: '漠', answer: ['막막할 막', '막막할', 'ばく'] },
    { question: '膜', answer: ['막 막', '막', 'まく'] },
    { question: '募', answer: ['모집할 모', 'つの(る)', 'ぼ'] },
    { question: '慕', answer: ['사모할 모', 'した(う)', 'ぼ'] },
    { question: '旦', answer: ['아침 단', '아침', 'たん、だん'] },
    { question: '但', answer: ['다만 단', 'ただ(し)', ''] },
    { question: '胆', answer: ['쓸개 담', '쓸개', 'たん'] },
    { question: '壇', answer: ['제단 단', '제단', 'だん、[たん]'] }
  ]
}
